He will rock you.
A Knight's Tale is a adventure, drama, romance film directed by Brian Helgeland.
William Thatcher, a knight's peasant apprentice, gets a chance at
glory when the knight dies suddenly mid-tournament.
Posing as a knight himself, William won't stop until he's crowned tournament
champion—assuming matters of the heart don't get in the way.
William Thatcher, played by Heath Ledger.
Count Adhemar, played by Rufus Sewell.
Jocelyn, played by Shannyn Sossamon.
Geoffrey Chaucer, played by Paul Bettany.
Kate, played by Laura Fraser.
Roland, played by Mark Addy.
A Knight's Tale is a 2001 American medieval action comedy film
written, co-produced and directed by Brian Helgeland.
The film stars Heath Ledger as William Thatcher, a peasant squire who poses as a knight and competes in tournaments, winning accolades and
acquiring friendships with such historical figures as Edward the Black Prince (James Purefoy) and Geoffrey Chaucer (Paul Bettany).
Its 14th-century story is intentionally anachronistic, with many modern pop
culture references and a soundtrack featuring 1970s music.
The film takes its name from Chaucer's story "The Knight's Tale", part of The
Canterbury Tales, and also draws several plot points from Chaucer's work.
A Knight's Tale was released by Columbia Pictures in
the United States on May 11, 2001.
It received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $117.5
million against a budget of $65 million.
The film explores themes of london, england,
poetry, rivalry, sword fight, knight.
The tone is emotional.